<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://0.0.0.0:8000/atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://0.0.0.0:8000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-05-12T03:22:50+05:30</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:8000/atom.xml</id><title type="html">n0nu11</title><author><name>n0nu11</name></author><entry><title type="html">Init 5: How it all Started</title><link href="http://0.0.0.0:8000/personal/2020/05/10/init5-how-it-all-started-up/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Init 5: How it all Started" /><published>2020-05-10T00:00:00+05:30</published><updated>2020-05-10T00:00:00+05:30</updated><id>http://0.0.0.0:8000/personal/2020/05/10/init5-how-it-all-started-up</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://0.0.0.0:8000/personal/2020/05/10/init5-how-it-all-started-up/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;whoami&quot;&gt;Whoami&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hi, My name is &lt;strong&gt;Waseem Akram&lt;/strong&gt; a.k.a &lt;strong&gt;n0nu11&lt;/strong&gt;. I make web apps, mobile apps, hunt bugs and design a little bit of user interfaces.
Well, I’m here to share you the wonderful but boring story of mine on how i got introduced to programming and making stuffs i like and much more. So get ready with the time machine, because we are going to travel back and forth to important moments in time. Lets go way back in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/tyqcJoNjNv0Fq/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;popcorn&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;journey-to-the-center-of-my-childhood&quot;&gt;Journey to the center of my childhood&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/kxAX99ncvbPk4/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;time machine&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been a computer enthusiast since my childhood. i like to play and break computers, explore unkown realm of computer world. Since then i’ve been curious how these magic boxes (computers) works. But a bummer, all i had is a mediocre desktop with limited and bad internet connection (Internet was’nt that famous those days). i started learning how basic components like printers, scanners, modems, etc,. works. Also i broke a lot of things from software (Operating systems by misconfiguration) to hardware in the way of exploration. Thanks to my dad for getting it fixed everytime.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Nothing interesting here. lets go a little forward in time now.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/chPWemdEXVzD0Zhcce/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;one year later&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;geek-not-nerd&quot;&gt;Geek! Not Nerd!!&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/s5u4GijpxgG4M/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;geek&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re here in 2012. I’m now a 13 year old calling myself a geek 😆, because that was the time i owned my first android phone, a old little micromax touch phone. I’ve used phones before, obviously an android but that belongs to my parents so i didn’t have much freedom to explore and break things. When i got my own phone, things started rigoring. i’ve learned a lot about android, iphones, their models and specs. i started tweaking around the android and installing various launchers to customise it the way i want. One fine day, i got introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rooting_(Android)&quot;&gt;rooting&lt;/a&gt; and you would’ve expect it. I Rooted my phone ignoring those scary warnings about the security issues and &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Brick_(electronics)&quot;&gt;bricking&lt;/a&gt; problems. Since then it changed the way i look at technology, How manufactures restrict users and how rooting breaks out the restriction and allows freedom to customise it in kernel level. Also that was the first time i got introduced to the term &lt;strong&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Hacking&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;. I installed a lot of tweaks, apps and patched games,etc, i pretty much enjoyed the process of rooting, the thrill of rooting (because if i brick, all i had to do is throw it away or spend some lump money to fix which will never be an option for me) and the benefits i gained after rooting. Apart from geeky stuffs i did Photoshop, Video editing using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Nero_Vision&quot;&gt;nero vision&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Lets leave. come on get in the time machine…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-siri-tragic&quot;&gt;The Siri tragic&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/xTkcERIlUQywNbOlYA/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;siri&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Huh! Its 2014. I’m 15 now, usual studies and exams bored me as always. One fine day, My dad bought me an iPhone 4, thats the first iPhone i had. That small incredible device is a masterpiece (Thanks to Steve jobs). The speed, smoothness and camera quality blew my mind. I loved every moment with it. Well time passed, you would’ve guessed it by now, &lt;strong&gt;ITS TIME TO JAILBREAK!!!&lt;/strong&gt; (Jailbreak is similiar to rooting). Again i started enjoying the benefits and freedom of tweaking.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There wasn’t a bluetooth file transfer feature in iPhone. Installed a tweak, Got it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;No file manager? no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Need some points or money in games? no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Download movies and music directly to iTunes? no problem.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jailbreak was like a buff for iPhone. Features were not just an imagination on those days. Then i got to know about &lt;strong&gt;SIRI&lt;/strong&gt;. Who didn’t want a talking smart assistant on their phone? But siri wasn’t natively available for iPhone 4. well lets install the SIRI using &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cydia&quot;&gt;cydia&lt;/a&gt; (its a package manager where you can install jailbreak tweaks) then. Lets risk it, what could go wrong right? fingers crossed 🤞.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/l0NwNrl4BtDD7JCx2/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;fingers crossed&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3orieTfp1MeFLiBQR2/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;please please&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Something went wrong with installation or dependencies i think, or it wasn’t just built for the iPhone 4.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My incredible iPhone got bricked 😭&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of the most regretting moment in my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3oEjHGnY8oB4BHVTP2/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;regret&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I could have just fixed it by formatting everything back to normal but internet was expensive those days and the firmware files was more than a gigs in size. No problem lets fix it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bought the internet pack and started downloading firmware files. &lt;strong&gt;Fingers crossed again 🤞.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3o7TKWzRShjaQxMGCk/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Download stuck&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;99% and FAILED!!!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/l3V0DBUt0chMCKBKo/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Fail&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t afford an another data pack. so i just gave up. Bye Bye iPhone 😢&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Sad times. lets get going…&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/xUOxf3aToeyp6EqURq/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;get going&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-game-of-roms&quot;&gt;The Game of Roms&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/iwVHUKnyvZKEg/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;GOT&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its Year 2014, 16 year old playing with android. Yeah i’m back to android after i messed up my iPhone. since then i had many android phones changed but in every android phone that i ever owned i did the same thing which is far from rooting. This time i started playing with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/List_of_custom_Android_distributions&quot;&gt;Android roms&lt;/a&gt; (Android roms are just modified android os) and different &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Kernel_(operating_system)&quot;&gt;kernels&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Booting&quot;&gt;bootloaders&lt;/a&gt;, recovery images,etc., available for the specific device i had. I would change the android rom as frequently as 2-3 per week just because it is fun to do. Basically i was addicted to that for a long time. I didn’t want to stay there but i wanted to learn how the operating system works. Thats how i got introduced to &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux&quot;&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Linux&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. I was a beginner and a windows user, so linux is scary as well as fun for the first time. Out of curiosity i learned &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bash_(Unix_shell)&quot;&gt;Bash Scripting&lt;/a&gt; and made &lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.xda-developers.com/android/software-hacking/mod-intelli-tweaks-t3159308&quot;&gt;Intelli Tweaks&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/intelli_tweaks.png&quot; alt=&quot;Intelli tweaks&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/intelli_tweaks_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Intelli tweaks 2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://forum.xda-developers.com/android/software-hacking/mod-intelli-tweaks-t3159308&quot;&gt;Click here to check it out&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Intelli tweaks&lt;/strong&gt; is, as the name suggests, Its tweaking script for rooted android phones which will buff your phone’s performance; You may have to take a look what it can do and make sure you read the comments too 😅. To be honest, i copied a few features from others and added to mine and made my tweaks look unique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Thats the first ever &lt;strong&gt;code/project&lt;/strong&gt; i ever wrote. &lt;strong&gt;Proud Moment&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/em&gt; 🎉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ![proud](https://media.giphy.com/media/l0He0cVv8lGggpruo/giphy.gif) --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/EbeugHT06pCr6/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;proud&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know what coding/programming or programming languages was back then. i was just doing everything out of curiousity by reading others works and guides online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sometime back then i also learned &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ethical Hacking&lt;/code&gt;. Basic XSS, SQL Injections, Directory path traversals and a quite few. One day an old indian website caught my eye with a admin login page. Well my curiosity didn’t stop me to apply SQL injection and the next minute i was inside the website’s admin panel. So creepy and Scary. while i was looking around i accidently clicked something that made the whole website go nuts and turn off. I didn’t wanna do anything but to comeout of it. The second day i found that it is fixed. Turned out the first website i &lt;strong&gt;hacked&lt;/strong&gt;. Another &lt;strong&gt;Proud Moment&lt;/strong&gt; 🎉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Whatever! Its time!. Lets jump a year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;oh-wait-i-was-able-to-c&quot;&gt;Oh wait, I was able to C&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’re in 2015, the year where it all started. I am a biology student in my highschool. Why? coz i actually chose biology over computer science because i thought choosing CS will bore me and also i love biology. One day our biology teacher was on leave so we stayed back in computer science class. That day was the quiz day for the CS class. I was sitting behind in the corner and answering almost all the questions correctly. CS teacher complemented me in front of whole class and asked me &lt;em&gt;” How are you able to answer all those questions? “&lt;/em&gt; (Honestly those were basic questions not rocket science). I answered &lt;em&gt;“Its basics and i feel computer science is too easy “&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One guy out of rage 😤 came to me and made a &lt;strong&gt;dare&lt;/strong&gt; asking me to compile a &lt;strong&gt;C program&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;em&gt;” I’m not asking you to run but just successfully compile a c program “&lt;/em&gt;  were his words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/MFCkrYZoqatqlJcQyh/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;dare&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I took it seriously and couldn’t forget it. I went home from school. Took my laptop started searching what the heck is C programming anyway? (Honestly i had no idea what is programming and programming languages are until that day).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Okay it is interesting, we can make computers do things whatever we want. Its basically a superpower! lets learn then?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I borrowed a old C programming book from a friend (Internet wasn’t a choice still). Started learning and wrote my first ever &lt;strong&gt;Hello World&lt;/strong&gt; program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-c highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#include&amp;lt;stdio.h&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(){&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;printf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s&quot;&gt;&quot;Hello Waseem!&quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;What? i made computer talk? Wow cool&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was a easy program. i mean the easiest program ever. So i didn’t have any problem until i started digging into it more. The more i learned the more i got warnings and errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/compilerror.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;error&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/iJCo9daAP0xugHhhfb/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;error&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But going through the book again with what i’ve learned clearly helped me solve all those problems. Its just the compiler is expecting me to write code that it can understand, not some gibberish like missing a semi colon or syntax errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;so sweet of you compiler.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was so curious. I learned variables, various data types, conditionals, loopings. But something stopped me progressing and thats Functions, Structs and Pointers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked myself &lt;em&gt;“What the heck is Functions? Structures? Pointers?”&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was tired understanding those and honestly i couldn’t. So i gave up hoping one day i could be able to understand those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Back to time machine&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-comeback&quot;&gt;The Comeback&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its early 2016 now. I’m on summer vactions after those long hectic board exams. Bored and got nothing to do except playing games. One day I’ve decided to join some instituion that can teach me C programming. Thats how i joined NIIT (National Institute of Information Technology) and opted for C, C++, Data Structures and Java course ( bad for wallet obviously but it turned out to be the best decision of my life ).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/elnu9VKIfTIzu/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;back&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was able to learn Functions, Structures and many more finally. Also this was my first ever biggest dumb program i wrote. It just finds the repeated character in a word that you enter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Alert: Its 150+ lines long, you may have to scroll fast.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/devwaseem/614aa4ffb4dc965d6418422968c34c1d.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was happy that i could write my own programs now. And i didn’t stop there. I completed learning C with all those things that i wasn’t able to understand in past. I eventually moved to C++ where i learned OOPS (Object Oriented Software Programming). Classes, Objects, Encapsulation, Abstraction, Polymorphism and all other was so much fun learning. i made sure i didn’t stop learning and making things. Some time later i moved to data structures, where i learned all those basic data structures form stacks, queues to trees and heaps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dawn-of-the-planet-of-the-apps&quot;&gt;Dawn of the planet of the Apps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/dZX3AduGrY3uJ7qCsx/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;code&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its Mid 2016, Passed C, C++, Data structures exams and moved on to &lt;strong&gt;Java&lt;/strong&gt; Class. But a bummer there, Only one Java class per week. So i have to wait until a week to learn something new. Dammit!. I didn’t had patience so i started learning Java on my own. Java was as fun as C and C++ because all the basic core concepts were the same, Syntax is different (Many other factors too but i’m simplifying here). Java classes bored me because i learned the concepts beforehand that they teach in class. I kept exploring, coding stuffs…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This is one of a early programs i wrote and i am proud of&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/java1.png&quot; alt=&quot;java&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devwaseem/number_to_pattern&quot;&gt;Click here to take a look&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One fine day, i got a million dollar question in my mind:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Why am i learning all this? What can i potentially make something better out of this?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thats when i really want to make use of my coding skill and started Googling. I found out i can make Android Apps since i know Java. Wait no more……&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started learning &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Android Programming&lt;/code&gt; in &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.udacity.com/&quot;&gt;Udacity&lt;/a&gt; and i gradually started making little basic android apps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I Moved to College a few months later. I always had a mind for solving problems. i saw a problem with timetables because it is new for me. wait no more i made a Time Table App that can not only show you what period is right now but also remind you whats next. Don’t mind the name please 😅.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/cserocks.png&quot; alt=&quot;cserocksapp&quot; /&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devwaseem/CSECROCKZZ&quot;&gt;Click here to take a look&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;That was my first successful android project&lt;/em&gt; 🎉&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since then, i was always curious to learn the concepts in depth be as it android or any programming languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Few months later, a Hackathon was conducted in my college where i created a app for our college bus which will update live status and route of the bus and also alert the students when the bus is near 100-300 meters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;(Unfortunately i lost the code, so i can’t able to link it here)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve made a lot of apps since then, met a lot of people, made friends, helped a lot of people, made some money too 🤑.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017,i bought a Macbook Pro 2012, until then i used a old dell laptop with 2 gigs ram. Imagine running android studio in &amp;lt; 2 Gb RAM. Its a nightmare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same year, I found a basic thing which whatsapp is missing. That is a video cutting features. i see a lot people want to upload videos or songs that are more than 30 seconds but unfortunately there isn’t a way unless they have to use a hard way by cutting the videos 30 seconds manually and upload the video as their stories in Whatsapp. Also there is no such app that can do it in the market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found that as an oppurtunity and made &lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.waseem.videotrimmerforwhatsapp&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Klip Kutter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. You would’ve guessed it by now. The App that can cut the videos into 30 seconds chunks which can make your life easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/klip%20kutter%201.png&quot; alt=&quot;klip kutter&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/klip%20kutter%202.png&quot; alt=&quot;klip kutter&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.waseem.videotrimmerforwhatsapp&amp;amp;hl=en_IN&quot;&gt;click here to take a look&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its an instant hit from day 1, I was the first in the market. After a week many apps copied the same functionality and started to pop in the play store.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/l3q2Z6S6n38zjPswo/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;success&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then i got introduced to iOS App Development and learned &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Swift&lt;/code&gt; programming language. Honestly &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Swift&lt;/code&gt; is a breeze and beautiful. Swift is the second most language i love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first iOS app i made was Venturious. It wasn’t my idea but a good friend/senior of mine &lt;a href=&quot;http://haashir.in/&quot;&gt;Haashir&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, i created Facepass, both for android and iOS. Its basically an app for anonymous messaging but powered with Facial Recognition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/facepass.png&quot; alt=&quot;facepass&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Producthunt: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/facepass&quot;&gt;https://www.producthunt.com/posts/facepass&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Github: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devwaseem/FacePass&quot;&gt;https://github.com/devwaseem/FacePass&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, the same year. I was hired by a company called Veda and assigned to make an iOS app for Learn America LMS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/learn%20america.png&quot; alt=&quot;lalms&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;fast-forward&quot;&gt;Fast Forward&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its 2018, I learned &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Kotlin&lt;/code&gt; which is a progamming language made for Android Apps. Kotlin is similar to Swift but unqiue in its own way. I love Coding using it. With that i decided to make an app. I eventually landed making an App for our college. Its an note keeper app which will provide notes for your class if someone already uploaded. The app was powered by a Chatbot that i made. It was uploaded to playstore intially but recently i removed it because i wasn’t getting a lot of users.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/notekeeper.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;notekeeper&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also started learning Web Technologies the same year. I learned Nodejs, React, Angular, Vuejs and made a lot of web apps for myself and my clients while i was proiving freelancing service. you can take a look at my &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/dvlp.er&quot;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt; for more stuffs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the Web apps are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/workshopui.png&quot; alt=&quot;workshop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is the website i’ve created for my college’s workshop event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2019, I created my profolio website for freelancing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/oldwebsite.png&quot; alt=&quot;my website&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://devwaseem.github.io/&quot;&gt;devwaseem.github.io&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later the same year and early 2019, i was also started learning and desiging UI (User interface).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are some of the designs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/checkoutui.png&quot; alt=&quot;checkout UI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/attendance%20app.png&quot; alt=&quot;attendace app&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/attendance%20login.png&quot; alt=&quot;attendance login&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/login_page.png&quot; alt=&quot;login page UI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/portfolioui.png&quot; alt=&quot;portfolio UI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/calcui.png&quot; alt=&quot;calculator UI&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Phewww.. Feeling tired after a long journey? lets go back to 2020 finally&lt;/em&gt; 😉.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/ZbCJfbQ0573bxaWyAH/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;back to 2020&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/3og0IS0LVHOuB3BCz6/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;back to 2020&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;present-and-infinity&quot;&gt;Present and Infinity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Its year 2020, finally. This year i started learning &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Ethical Hacking&lt;/code&gt; again. Why? you ask. I know i am good in programming at the same time i love learning in depth and exploring how internals works. The term Hacking isn’t what i perceive as some guy doing bad things but as the guy who enjoys breaking and learning stuffs in depth. Basically i want to be a security researcher coz i love providing security and breaking it. Even my college final year project is based on the security field. i’ve loved breaking stuffs and learning things in depth as you could’ve known by know if you read all the above sections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m currently learning and breaking stuffs in a safe way with various labs and platforms. One of the platform is tryhackme which provides a lab setup to learn and break systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/badge/20120&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve also made a simple script called AnonymousBash. Which as name suggests, it will proxy all your bash commands by tunneling it through TOR network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/AnonymousBash.png&quot; alt=&quot;AnonymousBash&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Link: &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devwaseem/AnonymousBash&quot;&gt;https://github.com/devwaseem/AnonymousBash&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also play Capture the Flag, which is a game for hackers or any cyber security enthusiast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main reason behind the birth of this blog is to post or share my writeups, research, and much more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I think thats it for now…&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.giphy.com/media/hpXxJ78YtpT0s/giphy.gif&quot; alt=&quot;bye&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;faq&quot;&gt;FAQ&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll answer few FAQ that i frequently get from many people i met.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;before-you-leave&quot;&gt;Before you leave&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have any constructive criticism or any questions you have, please drop a email at root@n0nu11.tech or ping me in &lt;a href=&quot;https://instagram.com/dvlp.er&quot;&gt;instagram&lt;/a&gt;. I’ll be happy to hear your feedbacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow me on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/devwaseem&quot;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/iamwaseem99&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/dvlp.er/&quot;&gt;Instagram&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/dvlprwaseem&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.linkedin.com/in/devwaseem/&quot;&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://tryhackme.com/p/r3d4ng37&quot;&gt;TryHackme&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.hackthebox.eu/profile/273182&quot;&gt;HackTheBox&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>n0nu11</name></author><category term="[&quot;personal&quot;]" /><category term="personal" /><summary type="html">Whoami</summary></entry></feed>